Ayumi,
步美
it's time for bed. Go take your bath.
该睡觉了哦 赶快去洗澡
Just a little longer? It's the good part!
再等一下行吗 现在正精彩呢
Aren't you going to go swimming tomorrow?
明天不是要去游泳吗
Fine.
好吧
Who are you?
你是谁
Are you Mr. Vampire?
吸血鬼先生吗
No.
不是
Flying is exhausting. I just need a rest.
我只是飞累了 停下来休息一下而已
I'm just a wizard.
我只不过是个魔法师
My little lady.
小小姐
He's over there. Don't let him get away.
在那边 别让那家伙逃了
Arrest Kaitou Kid!
快抓住怪盗基德
Farewell,
再见了
my little lady.
小小姐
What? You saw Kaitou Kid?
什么 你看到了怪盗基德
Really, Ayumi?
真的吗 步美
Yes, he's so handsome.
真的 他好帅哦
He really is Heisei era's Lupin.
真不愧是平成年代的鲁邦啊
What are you going to do, Heisei era's Holmes?
那么你这个平成年代的福尔摩斯打算怎么办呢
Don't be stupid,
笨蛋
one day I'll definitely catch him.
我当然总有一天会让他束手就擒
(Detective Conan The Last Wizard of the Century)
名侦探柯南 世纪末的魔术师
I am Shinichi Kudo, a high school detective.
我是高中生侦探工藤新一
When I was at an amusement park with Ran,
当我跟青梅竹马的同学毛利兰去游乐园玩时
I witnessed a man in black in the midst of a suspicious transaction.
却目击了黑衣人进行可疑交易的现场
While caught up in watching the deal...
当时我只顾着偷看交易
I failed to notice his partner sneaking up behind me.
竟然没发现他的同伙从背后靠近
That man forced me to swallow poison...
我被那个男人强行灌下毒药
When I woke up,
等我醒来时
my body had shrunk!
发现身体竟然缩小了
If they know that Kudo Shnichi is still alive,
如果被他们知道工藤新一还活着
they'd try to kill me
一定会再来取我的性命
and even my families and friends.
而且还将危及我身边的亲人
So I listened to Hiroshi Agasa's advice
在阿笠博士的建议下
and hid my true identity.
我决定隐藏自己的真实身份
When Ran asked about my name,
当小兰问及我的名字时
the name Conan Edogawa suddenly hit me.
情急之下我化名为江户川柯南
In order to get more information about that Black Organization,
为了得到那些家伙的情报
I went to live with Ran, whose father is a private detective.
我便住进了父亲是侦探的小兰家
I am Kogoro Mouri, the famous detective.
我是名侦探毛利小五郎
People call him 'Sleeping Kogoro'.
被称为沉睡的小五郎
Actually, that's because...
其实是因为
With a tranquilizing wristwatch, I put him to sleep,
我用手表型麻醉枪让他沉睡
and imitate his voice with the voice-changing bow-tie,
再使用蝴蝶结型变声器
and then solve all the cases.
模仿他的声音解开案件
The two objects were both invented by Hiroshi Agasa.
这两样都是阿笠博士的发明
Though it's hard to tell, he is actually a genius.
虽然表面上看不太出来但博士其实是个天才
His other inventions include
其他还有 带涡轮引擎的滑板
criminal tracking glasses,
犯人追踪眼镜
power assisted kick shoes and other stuffs.
脚力增强鞋等
He invented lots of special things for me.
接连帮我做出独一无二的发明
For example, this upgraded skateboard could be used at nighttime
特别是这个改良的滑板 只要在白天充好电
after it stores enough solar energy during the day.
晚上也可以使用30分钟
Apart from Agasa,
而知道我真实身份的
there are two others who know my true identity,
除了博士以外还有两个人
Heiji Hattori, a high school detective in Kansai
关西的高中生侦探服部平次
and Ai Haibara, a transfer student.
以及转学生灰原哀
Haibara used to be a member of the Black Organization.
她原本是黑衣男人的同伙
In order to escape the organization...
因为想脱离组织
She took the same drug as I did,
吃了和我一样的药
and her body shrank as well.
身体也因此而被缩小
While I am investigating the Black Organization,
我一方面追查着黑衣人组织
I keep running into tricky cases.
另一方面又不断的遇到棘手案件
And now, a new rival appears...
现在我又碰到了一个强劲对手
The silver lining in the darkness and chaos.
在混沌和疑惑的黑暗中露出一线曙光
Though my body was shrunken, my mind is still clever.
人虽变小了头脑依然灵活
I am the famous detective who can solve all the cases.
无所不知的名侦探
Only one truth will prevail!
真相永远只有一个
The thief with the case number 1412, better known as Kaitou Kid,
怪盗1412号 通称怪盗基德
has committed 134 heists,
总共犯案134起
15 of which
其中15件在国外
in the USA, France, Germany
美国 法国 德国等
and 12 other overseas countries.
足迹遍布12个国家
The jewels he has stolen amount to 152 pieces,
盗取的宝石共152件
worth a total of 38,725,000,000 yen.
盗窃总额达387亿2千5百万日元
He sent a notice letter yesterday:
这个怪盗基德昨天寄来新的预告函
"From the lion of dusk to the maiden of the dawn...
从黄昏的狮子到拂晓的少女
when the second hand on the clock indicates the twelfth symbol,
当没有秒针的时钟刻下第12个文字时
From a multi-storied building with a shining sky,
从发光的天之楼阁降临
I shall call upon you and gratefully accept the Memories Egg...
拜领回忆之卵
The Last Wizard of the Century.
世纪末的魔术师
Kaitou Kid
怪盗基德
The Memories Egg he mentioned in the letter
预告函中提到的回忆之卵
refers to a treasure found in storage last month that's owned by the Suzuki Group.
就是上个月从铃木财团宝库中发现的
Originating during the Romanov Dynasty,
罗曼诺夫王朝的秘宝
it is one of the Imperial Easter Eggs.
也就是皇帝的复活节之卵
This imperial Easter egg
这个皇帝的复活节之卵
was a gift from the Russian czar to his wife on Easter Sunday.
是在复活节时俄国皇帝送给皇后的
It was made by famous jeweler Faberge.
由宝石制作家法贝热(Faberge)制作
Among all the eggs he made from 1885 to 1916, only 50 eggs were found.
1885年到1916年间只做了50个
This egg which was just discovered will be the fifty-first piece.
而这次发现的这个则是第51个蛋
It will be displayed in the Modern Arts museum which is about to open in Osaka Park
这第51个蛋将于8月3日起在大阪城公园内
from August 23rd.
即将开幕的铃木美术馆内展出
Then, about the code in the letter,
然后是关于暗号的内容
Officer Nakamori.
中森警官
Yes.
好的
Firstly, "From the lion of dusk to the maiden of the dawn"
首先是从黄昏的狮子到拂晓的少女这句
refers to the evening of the last day of the zodiac Leo, August 22nd, to
这是指狮子座最后一天8月22日黄昏开始
to the sunrise on the first day of the zodiac Virgo.
直到处女座第一天的黎明这段时间
So it indicates the day he plans to commit his heist.
这代表了犯案的日子
"when the second hand on the clock indicates the twelfth symbol",
没有秒针的时钟刻下第12个文字
I think it must be a reference to the time of the crime,
我猜想这是代表犯案的时刻
but I don't have a definitive answer yet.
可是还没能解读出来
At last, "From a multi-storied building with a shining sky",
最后是从发光的天之楼阁降临
I think it indicates the place where Kaidou Kid will show up,
就是天守阁 也就是大阪城
which is Tenshukaku, also known as Osaka Castle.
表示了怪盗基德现身的地点
Anyway, the notice implies that,
总而言之预告函的内容是
between the evening of August 22nd and sunrise on the 23rd...
8月22日黄昏至23日黎明之间
Kaitou Kid will appear at the main tower of Osaka castle,
怪盗基德将出现在大阪城天守阁
and steal the Imperial Easter egg.
并盗取皇帝的复活节之卵
This time, we'll work with the police in Osaka.
这次我们和大阪府警共同行动
Following Mr. Suzuki's wishes,
并且在铃木先生的要求下
we asked Kogoro Mouri to help with the investigation.
邀请到了名侦探毛利小五郎协助调查
Hello, everyone,
大家好
we have to protect the Easter Egg at all costs,
此次我们的目的是死守复活节之卵
even if we fail to capture him.
就算让犯人逃走也要保住它
How could we let go of him so easily?
我们怎么可以如此轻易的放过他
The Easter Egg means nothing.
复活节之卵算什么
Listen up, you lot!
知道吗 各位
Our dignity and reputation is on the line now,
赌上我们警察的威信和骄傲
we have to put that asshole behind bars!
一定要把那个混蛋小偷投进监狱
We have to do it.
绝对 绝对要做到
The, the task seems tricky.
接 接了一件棘手的差事
Ran, over here.
小兰 这里这里
Sonoko.
园子
What a fancy car.
高级大轿车
As expected of the Suzuki Group!
不愧是铃木财团
Because today is a special day.
因为今天很特别啊
Special?
特别
Because I can meet my dream lover Kaitou Kid-sama.
因为要见到我一直仰慕的怪盗基德殿下
I have to take it seriously.
不隆重一点怎么行
Geez, Sonoko...
园子真是的
Your dream lover, Kid-sama?
仰慕的基德殿下
By the way, our driver is my dad's secretary, Nishino.
对了 为我们开车的是爸爸的秘书西野先生
Nice to meet you.
请多指教
He has been traveling all over the world
他一直旅居在世界各国
and speaks English, French and German fluently.
英文 法文和德文都很流利
Awesome.
好棒哦
Agasa, this is outrageous.
博士太狡猾了
How could you only let Conan go to Osaka?
只让柯南一个人去大阪
I really want to meet Kid again.
我好想再见基德一面哦
Conan's always one step ahead of us.
捷足先登可是他的拿手好戏
Don't talk like that.
别这样说嘛
How about having some watermelon to cool off your anger?
吃点西瓜消消气如何
Great.
太棒了
I'm eating now.
开动
Wait,
等一下
you can only eat it before you solve my riddle.
先解开谜题才能吃
Are you for real Agasa?
不要啦 博土
You have to.
怎么可以
What would the world come to if children were raised having everything handed to them!
小孩子养成太轻易就得到东西的习惯就不好了
Listen closely,
听好哦
I have many grandchildren, how old are they?
我有很多个孙子 是几岁
You have grandchildren?
博士有孙子啊
That's just a riddle.
这只是谜题啦
Well, we can't think of any answer because Conan's not here.
果然 柯南不在我们就想不出来了
Then, what about the watermelon?
那这些西瓜怎么办
Zero.
0岁
They're still eggs.
还是一个蛋呢
'Washi' is a pun on 'eagle'
我(washi)和鹫(washi)日文发音相同
'ooku no mago' in other words would be 'tamago'- a pun for eggs.
很多个孙子也就是多孙(tamago)和卵(tamago)同音
An egg is zero years old.
卵当然是0岁
Correct. Ai, you are brilliant.
标准答案 不愧是小哀
I knew you would get the answer.
我就知道你一定会解开
Haibara.
灰原你
You are so clever.
好厉害
Haibara is also one of the Detective Boys,
灰原也是少年侦探团的一员吧
so that means,
也就是说
let's start to eat.
开动
What will happen to the egg over there?
那边的蛋又会有什么进展呢
Show me what you've got,
让我开开眼界吧
Kudo.
工藤
This place is heavily guarded.
好严密的警戒啊
Even an ant couldn't get in.
连只蚂蚁都进不去
Of course.
那当然哦
We are dealing with Kaitou Kid this time after all.
因为对手是怪盗基德嘛
He is known as...
不管怎么说他可是…
the elusive and changeable gentleman thief
神出鬼没自由变化的怪盗绅士
who can crack all kinds of defense and break into any impenetrable treasury
再森严的戒备 再坚固的金库
like he has some kind of magic.
他都能如同施展魔法一般快速破解
Also, he's also a master of disguise who can even copy others' looks, voices and personalities.
还是个甚至连外型 声音和性格都能模仿的化装高手
Come on,
真是的
this time our enemy truly is tough.
这次真是碰到棘手的对手了
Kudo.
工藤
Hattori.
服部
It's that guy again.
又是这家伙
Hey,
真是的
why do you always call Conan by Kudo's name?
为什么服部你每次都对着柯南叫工藤啊
Sorry, sorry.
对不起 对不起
Because his eyes are just like Kudo's.
因为这家伙的眼神很像工藤
So the name just slipped out of my mouth.
不知不觉就叫了出来
You are such an idiot.
真像个白痴
You've been saying, 'Kudo's coming' since this morning.
今天从一大早起来就嚷着工藤要来工藤要来
I think you better go see a doctor.
我看你最好去医院让医生看看
Is he Heiji Hattori, the high school detective in Kansai?
他就是关西的高中生侦探服部平次吗
He's a good-looking guy.
长得挺帅的嘛
Stop.
不行不行
He and Kazuha are childhood sweethearts.
他与和叶可是青梅竹马哦
Though they always bicker with each other like that,
虽然他们常常这样斗嘴
they are actually a sweet couple.
感情可是非常好哦
I can tell.
光看看就知道了
They are just like you and Shinichi.
跟你和新一是一模一样
I want a boyfriend who's also my childhood friend.
我也好想要青梅竹马的男朋友啊
Hi, Mr. Mouri.
是毛利先生
Thanks for traveling all the way here.
谢谢你特地远道而来
Hello.
你好
Ran, Conan, you are here too.
小兰和柯南也来啦
Sonoko, can you introduce them to me?
园子 这两位是
They are Heiji Hattori and Kazuha Toyama.
是服部平次和远山和叶 爸爸
Heiji was called the high school detective in Kansai.
平次被称为关西的高中生侦探
He's pretty famous in Kansai.
在关西相当有名哦
That's perfect. I'd really appreciate your help.
太好了 那也要拜托你了
I have it covered, old man.
包在我身上 大叔
You little...
你这臭小子
how dare you call the chairman of Suzuki Corporation an old man?
竟然对着铃木财团的会长喊大叔
It's fine, Mr. Mouri.
没关系 毛利先生
Let me introduce,
我帮你们介绍一下
this is Sergei Ovchinnikov,
这位是俄罗斯大使馆一等秘书
a high-level representative of the Russian Embassy.
西鲁·欧夫钦尼可夫先生
It's nice to meet you.
请多指教
The one next to him is an art dealer I invited here,
旁边这位是我找来的美术商
Shoichi Inui.
乾将一先生
This is Seiran Hoshi. She's a historian specializing in the Romanov Dynasty.
她是罗曼诺夫王朝研究家浦思青兰小姐
Hello.
你好
And this is Ryu Sagawa,
这位是申请来采访并拍摄复活节之卵的
a freelance reporter who applied to report the Easter Egg.
自由摄影家 寒川龙先生
Nice meeting you.
请多指教
So what's the appraised value of the egg?
那么他们鉴定下来价值是多少
800 million yen.
8亿
What? 800 million?
什么 8亿
If you are willing to sell it, I could offer you more.
如果你愿意卖 我可以再多出一点
Mr. Chairman,
会长先生
the Imperial Easter Egg belongs to Russia.
皇帝的复活节之卵是俄罗斯的东西
You should donate it to the Russian National Museum
与其卖给这种来路不明的商人
instead of selling it to a shady broker.
请务必捐赠给我们俄罗斯美术馆
"Shady," you say!?
你说我来路不明
Great,
好耶好耶
you guys are making a better story than the egg.
拍人说不定比拍那颗蛋更有趣
You seem pretty cool about this.
你一副事不关己的模样
If you really are a historian of Romanov Dynasty,
如果你真的是罗曼诺夫王朝研究家的话
you should want that egg the most.
应该比任何人都更想要得到那颗蛋才对
That's right. But I don't have 800 million yen...
是啊 可是8亿对我来说太…
That's not wrong.
说得也是
Even I could only scrape together 200 million.
硬凑的话我也只能勉强凑出2亿
Kaitou Kid is not the only one who's going after that egg.
不只是怪盗基德大家都对那颗蛋虎视耽耽呢
Anyway, let's talk about the egg at a later date.
总之关于蛋的事改天再谈
I see.
明白了
Okay, it's time for me to leave.
好吧 今天我就先告辞了
Mr. Chairman, I brought the egg here.
会长 我把蛋拿来了
Thanks.
辛苦了
Put it on the table.
放在桌上吧
Yes, sir.
好的
Everyone, please sit down.
各位 请坐
Can we see the egg now?
我们可以看那颗蛋吗
It doesn't look very impressive.
外表看起来不怎样啦
When I was young, it was one of my toys.
小时候还被我拿来当玩具玩呢
Your toy?
玩具
This is the Imperial Easter Egg.
这就是皇帝的复活节之卵
Nishino, please prepare some refreshments for everyone.
西野 替大家倒杯冷饮
Yes, sir.
好的
It's not as pretty as I thought.
没有想象中的漂亮
It's like an ostrich egg.
好像鸵鸟蛋一样
This could be opened, right?
这个可以打开吧
Yes, you are pretty clear about this.
是啊 你很清楚嘛
It contains the model of Tsar Nicholas' family,
这里面是尼古拉皇帝一家的模型
all made of gold.
全部都是黄金打造的
Marvelous.
真是不得了啊
There's an interesting mechanism in this egg.
这颗蛋还有个很有趣的机关
This is interesting.
这个有意思
The design drawing of this egg's internal structure
根据以前法贝热记录的资料中
was recorded in Faberge's paper,
有记载着这颗蛋的内部设计图
which shows that this egg is authentic.
也正是因为这些记载才能确定这颗是真品
Is its English name 'Memories Egg' translated from Russian?
回忆之卵是俄语翻成英语的吗
Yes.
是啊
The name is ВОСПОМИНАНИЕ,
俄语是ВОСПОМИНАНИЕ
the meaning of which is memories.
翻成日文就是回忆
Why does turning the pages of the book represent memories?
为什么翻书就是回忆呢
You fool.
笨蛋
The Tsar called his children over and told them stories on the book.
皇帝把孩子们叫过来听他念书里的故事
Isn't that a good memory for them?
不就是他们美好的回忆吗
Are the shining things inside the egg gems?
蛋里面闪闪发光的是宝石吗
No, that's just glass.
不 那只是玻璃
This is the gift which the Tsar presented to his wife.
这是皇帝送给皇后的礼物耶
Isn't that odd?
不觉得很奇怪吗
When the 51st egg was made,
可是在制作第51颗蛋的时候
Russia was in financial crisis.
据说俄国陷入了财政困难时期
What's weirder is Kid's letter.
比这个更奇怪的是那封基德的预告函
A multi-storied building with a shining sky...
发光的天之楼阁
Why would Osaka Castle be shining?
为什么大阪城会发光
Dummy.
傻瓜
Mr. Taikou who built Osaka Castle
建造大阪城的太阁先生
wanted Osaka Castle to witness the development Osaka
就是要让大阪城见证大阪的发展
because the castle is like a shining light for the city.
就像大阪之光一样
That's right.
没错
Kid will definitely show up
基德会在大阪城的天守阁出现
at the Osaka Castle. However,
这一点绝对没错 可是
we still haven't figured out what the words
没有秒针的时钟刻下第12个文字的时候
"when the second hand on the clock indicates the twelfth symbol" means.
这句话的意思怎么也搞不懂
Could it be the 12th letter of Gojuon?
是不是日文50音图的第12个字呢
The 12th letter of Gojuon?
50音图的第12个
That's しシ(shi), so it's four o'clock.
是しシ(shi) 那就是4(shi)点啦
No, the hint Kid gave can't be that simple.
不 基德的暗号不会这么简单
I know it, Officer.
我知道了 警察先生
It's not the Gujuon, but the Latin alphabet.
不是日文的50音图 而是英文字母
Latin alphabet?
英文字母
The twelfth letter of the alphabet is L.
英文字母的第12个字母是L
Which refers to,
也就是
three o'clock?
3点吗
As expected of a renowned detective! What a brilliant idea.
不愧是名侦探 破解得真漂亮
That's right. 3 o'clock in the morning is before dawn,
没错 凌晨3点还在破晓前
this fit the note "the dawn of the maiden".
这和拂晓的少女也符合
Just you wait, Kaitou Kid.
你等着吧 怪盗基德
I'll bring you to justice this time.
这次我一定要将你绳之以法
I got an "Excellent Luck"!
我大吉耶
Let me see.
哪里哪里
"Awaited person...You'll reunite with your love"!
等待的人 会和恋人相逢
Then that'd mean Shinichi, right?
指的是新一的事吧
That's great. This time I have to meet him.
太好了 这次让我也见见他吧
I am right here.
我就在这里
How do we kill time before 3 o'clock in the morning?
那么凌晨3点前我们要怎么打发时间呢
Anyway, let's go eat something delicious.
总之先去吃点好吃的吧
Kazuha, you should show them around.
和叶 你带她们两位去玩吧
What about you?
平次呢
I'll take care of this little guy here.
我招呼这个小鬼呀
Why? Let's go together.
为什么 一起走嘛
Boys should hang out with boys.
男生和男生在一起比较好
What do you say, Co... Co... Conan?
你说是吗 柯…柯…柯南
Yeah.
是的
You better change that habit quickly.
给我早点养成习惯
Come on, what's that attitude?
干嘛 那么凶啊
You want me to expose your identity?
要我拆穿你吗
Please... please get used to calling me Conan.
请…请努力习惯起来
That's good.
很好很好
Don't forget to smile
拜托别人的时候
when you ask a favor from others.
可不能忘记微笑哦
That's weird. Why are they so close?
奇怪 他们两个为什么那么要好
Anyway, girls should hang out with girls.
管他的 女生就要跟女生在一起
Let's find some hot guys in the city of waves
在浪花之城找些酷酷的男生
and let them give us a treat.
来请我们吃饭吧
Do you want to go to Ebisubashi?
那你们要不要去戎桥看看
You are thinking about the twelfth letter riddle, aren't you?
你在想第12个文字的事吧
Yeah.
是啊
It'll be more reasonable if it's in Russian alphabet.
如果L是俄文字母的话还容易理解
Russian letters?
俄文字母
The twelfth letter in Russian alphabet is K like the English letter K.
俄文是К 也就是英文K
But we can't tell what time is it from letter K.
K就不是指针的形状了
Also, I feel the words at the end of the letter,
还有预告函最后面的
"The Last Wizard of the Century" also very strange.
世纪末的魔术师 也觉得很奇怪
What an annoying guy.
真是个讨厌的家伙
He never used that name until now.
至今为止他从来没有用过这个名字
Plus, Kid only steals gems.
而且一向只偷取宝石的基德
Why is he interested in this egg?
为什么这次会看上这颗蛋
Checkmate.
将军
By the way, which lot did you draw?
对了你刚刚抽的是什么签
I haven't even looked at it yet.
我根本还没看
Why?
为什么
That's the important lot which could predict the result of the battle with Kid.
那可是预测和基德对决结果的很重要的签啊
Come on.
真是的
It's good fortune. But the words on it are meaningless.
小吉啊 这等于没说嘛
How can we know if we'll win the batter or not?
这样根本不知道和基德的较量谁赢谁输
The one you are waiting for will come.
等待的人会来
Travel: Don't go. Your secret will be exposed.
旅行：秘密会被揭穿 不要去
No way.
不可能吧
No freaking way.
不可能啦
The lots from that shrine are always right.
这里的签很准哦
You are lying.
你骗人
It's true.
是真的
Let's go to the restaurant.
去吃个便饭吧
We already know that Kid will arrive at three o'clock tomorrow morning.
已经知道基德明早三点才来
We only need to come back before that.
在这之前回来就好了
Fine.
好啊
Mr. Chairman, we are almost finished.
会长 差不多了
Okay, thank you.
好的 拜托你了
Are you going to put it in the exhibition room?
要移到展览室吗
We'll put a fake one there.
放过去的是赝品
A fake one?
赝品
We used to
以前我们总是
put the treasure at the place where Kid announced in the letter like idiots.
像白痴一样老老实实的把猎物放在基德预告的地方
That's why he always gets what he wants.
所以才会让他得逞
This time we are planning to put the egg at a place he doesn't know.
这次我们打算让他找不到这颗蛋的所在之处
I see.
原来如此
Where are you going to put it then?
那要放在哪里呢
I won't tell you that.
我不会告诉你的
Only my two subordinates and I know it.
只有我和两个部下知道
Of course, neither of them
当然他们两个
is Kid in disguise.
绝对不会是基德化装的
What are you doing?
你干嘛
You might be Kid in disguise too.
因为你也可能是基德化装的
So are you.
那你也有可能
What are you doing?
做什么
My name is Natsumi Kosaka.
我叫香坂夏美
This is my family steward, Mr. Sawabe.
这位是管家泽部先生
There's something I want to say to your chairman
关于简介上皇帝的复活节之卵
about the Imperial Easter Egg on this pamphlet.
我们有些事想向会长说
Unfortunately, our chairman has gone out.
很不巧会长已经出去了
If you don't mind, I can relay a message for you.
不介意的话 和我谈也可以
There's something wrong with the picture of the egg.
这张蛋的照片不对
It looks different from the sketch my great-grandpa made.
和我曾祖父留下来的画不一样
That's funny.
这个很有趣哦
If 3 a.m. looks like a "L",
凌晨3点是L的话
now we almost have a "へ" (he).
现在是へ(he)
へ (he).
へ
It's seven thirteen now.
现在是7点13分
At seven twenty, it'll be exactly like a へ.
如果7点20分 就更像へ了
Between the dusk of the Lion and the dawn of the Virgin.
从黄昏的狮子到拂晓的少女
The twelfth letter is へ.
从头数到第12个字正是へ
Hattori,
服部
Kid didn't mean 3 a.m. in the letter,
基德预告的时间不是凌晨3点
but seven twenty at night.
而是晚上7点20分
What did you say?
你说什么
Where are you going, Kudo?
你要去哪里 工藤
To Osaka Castle.
大阪城
Keep a close eye on that egg.
你给我看着那颗蛋
It's raining.
下雨了
The weather forecast said that it would be sunny.
气象预报明明说是晴天
Wait, Kudo.
等一下 工藤
The Shining Sky chamber doesn't refer to Osaka Castle
天之楼阁不是天守阁
but the Tsuuten Tower.
是通天阁
Tsuuten Tower?
通天阁
There's a weather station on top of Tsuuten Tower that shines.
通天阁的塔顶是发光的天气预报显示屏
What do you mean?
你说什么
Ladies and Gentlemen,
Ladies and Gentlemen(女士们 先生们)
Now, let's get this show on the road!
好 演出就要开始了
What... what is that?
那…那是什么
It's fireworks,
是烟火
such an enjoyment in summer.
正好是夏天的风物志
It's so beautiful.
好漂亮
The fireworks in Osaka are also splendid.
大阪的烟火也特别灿烂耶
That's weird.
奇怪了
Today is not the day for fireworks.
今天不是放烟火的日子啊
Officer, there are fireworks being set off at Osaka Castle.
警官 大阪城那边在放烟火
A lot of fireworks.
而且数量很多
Shut up, that's not Kid.
别吵 那不是基德
We've still got more than 7 hours till he shows up.
他预告的时间还有7个多小时
He will never guess that
他绝对想不到
the egg will be hidden in such an insignificant warehouse.
这颗蛋会藏在这种不起眼的仓库里
Hattori, where's Tsuuten Tower?
服部 通天阁在哪里
Over there.
那边
But there's no firework.
可是那边没有烟火
The fireworks at Osaka Castle
他在大阪城放烟火
are an attempt to divert attention away from Tsuuten Tower.
就是为了把目光从通天阁引开
But why?
可是为什么
Why did he choose Tsuuten Tower?
为什么他会选在通天阁
Damn it, it's too late to go to Tsuuten Tower.
可恶 现在去通天阁也来不及了
Let's stay here and wait for Kid to come.
我们埋伏在这里等基德过来
Mr. Nishino, where is the egg now?
西野先生 蛋现在放在哪里
Officer Nakamori took it to somewhere else.
中森警官把它移到别处去了
What?
什么
Next.
接下来
Blackout.
停电
What is it this time? What happened?
这次又怎么了 发生什么事
That's a bit odd.
有点奇怪哦
Let's have a drink under the moonlight.
在月光下喝上一杯
This is so refreshing.
真是风雅啊
Don't panic.
别慌
Use the emergency power, now.
马上自行发电 快点
Yes, sir.
是
I know what he's up to.
我知道他的目的了
Hoenzaka Empire Hospital,
大元坂帝国医院
Dojima Century Hotel,
堂岛世纪饭店
Tenma Emergency Center,
天满急救医疗中心
Channel 10 Hotel, Naniwa TNS Hospital,
10频道饭店 浪花TNS医院
Kansai World Hotel.
关西世界饭店
Bingo.
砰
Out of the way, you can't turn right.
让开 不能右转弯了
The cars on the straight lane go first.
直行车优先
He knew that the egg was transferred to somewhere else.
他知道真的蛋已经被移往别处
In order to know where that egg is hidden,
为了知道藏蛋之处
he caused a blackout in the centre of the city
先让市中心全部停电
so some places have to use the emergency power.
诱使他们自行发电
Except for the hotels and hospitals, the place where there's light should be his target.
然后 除了饭店医院以外有灯光的地方就是
Kid.
基德
Shoot.
可恶
Crap, it's a dead end.
糟了 死路
Get on the motorcycle, Kudo.
快上车 工藤
I get it now.
原来如此
Tsuuten Tower is the best place
要找到亮灯的地方
to find lights.
通天阁是最适合的位置
Before he sent out that letter,
他在发出预告函之前
he already knew that this would happen.
早就知道会有这样的结果
He also knew that that place wouldn't be heavily guard
而且还知道为了不让目标地点引人注目
in order not to draw too much attention.
警戒不会很严
If we can't get there quickly,
不赶快过去
the egg will be stolen.
东西会被偷走
Hattori,
服部
wait here.
你在这里等着
What? Hey, Kudo.
什么 喂 工藤
Kid.
基德
Damn it.
可恶
No.
糟了
Hurry up, Kudo.
快点 工藤
He needs to fly on his hang glider against the mild wind.
滑翔翼起飞需要不太强的逆风
You mean he'll fly against the wind?
也就是说要顶风起飞吗
He's starting to descend!
他开始降低高度了
Up ahead is Osaka Bay.
前面是大阪湾
He's gotta land there.
基德一定会降落的
Hattori, are you all right?
服部 你不要紧吧
What are you doing here? Go after him.
你还在做什么 快点去追
I won't let you go if he gets away.
让他逃了我可不饶你
Hattori.
服部
Are you OK, young man?
你还好吗 小兄弟
Please call an ambulance and the police here.
麻烦你叫救护车和警察
Wait here, Hattori.
你等着吧 服部
That's...
这个是
The injury.
这个伤口
The egg is still here.
蛋没事
This is Kid's monocle.
这是基德的单片眼镜
He was shot and fell into the sea?
难道他被击中掉到了海里
Then, who was that guy...
还有刚才那个人究竟是…
At that night, a wide-range search for Kid's body went underway.
当晚警察拼命的在海域里搜寻
However, the police found nothing and nobody knew if Kid's still alive.
还是无法确认基德的生死
The next day, the exhibition was cancelled
翌日 为了调查蛋有无损坏
because they needed to check if the egg was damaged.
紧急停止展示
The egg was transported to Tokyo on Suzuki's cruise liner.
利用铃木家的邮轮运回东京
My great grandpa's name was Kiichi.
我的曾祖父名叫喜一
He was a craftsman working for Faberge
他曾在法贝热的工厂中担任工人
and married a Russian woman.
并在当地和俄罗斯女性结婚
After the second year of the revolution, he and his wife returned to Japan.
革命爆发后的第二年两人一起回到日本
My great grandma had a daughter
曾祖母生了个女婴
but died soon after giving birth.
可是不久曾祖母就过世了
Nine years later, my great grandpa also passed away.
9年后曾祖父45岁时也过世了
So their daughter,
那位女婴
is my grandma.
是我的祖母
My grandfather and my parents
祖父和我的父母
died in a car accident when I was five.
在我5岁时因为车祸丧生
I was raised by my grandma.
我是祖母抚养长大的
However the elder mistress herself had passed away last month.
可是老太太也在上个月过世了
I'm a baker in Paris.
我在巴黎做西点师
This time I came back to Japan to sort through my grandma's stuffs.
特地回国来整理祖母的遗物
As a result, I found an old sketch which belonged to my great grandpa.
结果发现了应该是曾祖父画的很旧的图纸
A middle part is missing.
中间破了
Memories.
回忆
This is the sketch of Memories Egg.
的确是回忆之卵
But this one has gems.
可是这上面镶嵌有宝石
Maybe the gems fell off.
是不是本来镶嵌的宝石后来掉了
Is it possible that there were originally two eggs.
会不会本来就有两个蛋
Because if there's only one egg,
因为如果这是一个蛋的话
the outlines don't align.
轮廓线合不起来啊
Is it possible that he drew two eggs on a large paper,
会不会本来是在很大的纸上画了两个蛋
and the middle part has gone missing?
而中间部份不见了
I see.
原来如此
But why is it called memories?
可是为什么要叫回忆呢
There's a mirror here.
这里有一片镜子
Crap, it fell out.
糟糕 掉了
What are you doing?
你在做什么啊
There's a small glass piece. I accidentally got it off.
有一小片镜子 不小心弄掉了
What?
什么
Conan.
柯南
It doesn't matter.
没关系啦
That glass is easy to take down.
那个镜子很容易拆下来的
It was put there afterwards.
好像是后来才装上去的
Wait, something has been printed on the glass.
奇怪 好像有照到什么
Could it be that?
这该不会是
Mr. Nishino, please turn off the light.
西野先生 麻烦你关灯
You took command here again. What do you want?
你又自作主张 想干嘛
Why... why would there be a picture?
为…为什么会出现图像
It's a secret mirror.
是魔镜
Secret mirror?
魔镜
I've heard of that before.
我听说过
It's a kind of magical mirror which only exists in Japan and China.
在日本和中国存在一种神奇的镜子
That's right.
是啊
The mirror has been through some special manufacturing procedures.
镜子经过特殊的处理
Some secret Catholics in Japan
以前日本有些秘密的天主教徒
used these secret mirrors to project crosses on the wall to worship in secret.
利用镜子反射在墙上的十字架偷偷的祈祷
Mr. Sawabe, the castle is...
泽部先生 这座城堡
Yes, it's Yokosuka Castle.
是的 是横须贺的城堡没错
Yokosuka Castle.
横须贺的城堡
The one which we always see on television commercials?
常常出现在广告中的那座城堡吗
Yes.
是的
It was built by my great grandfather and inherited by my great grandma.
是我曾祖父盖的 曾祖母一直管理着
So, this castle belongs to Kosaka's family.
那这是香坂家的城堡喽
Natsumi,
夏美小姐
your great grandfather made the two eggs, didn't he?
这两个蛋是你曾祖父做的吧
Before the Russian Revolutions, your great grandpa and his wife made the two eggs.
你的曾祖父在俄国革命之前
After that, they took the eggs with them when they came back to Japan.
和他夫人一起制作了这两个蛋 然后带回日本
Maybe they have sold the gems from the second egg
也许把这第二颗蛋上的宝石部分变卖之后
to build Yokusaka Castle.
才盖了横须贺的城堡
The second egg must be hidden somewhere in that castle.
而第二颗蛋则藏在城堡里的某个地方
Your great grandpa left the message in the other egg
然后把藏在城堡里这一暗示
through the secret mirror.
通过这个魔镜镶嵌在其它的蛋里面
Actually, besides the sketch, I also found this key.
其实除了图纸以外还有这把旧钥匙
You found this?
这个也是吗
This is key to the place where the second egg was hidden.
这就是藏第二颗蛋的地方的钥匙
The dream egg which has gems inside.
镶嵌着宝石的梦幻之卵
It'll be worth more than 1 billion yen...
如果找到的话价值10亿
No, 1.5 billion yen,at least.
不 一定值15亿以上
Is that the real reason why Kid wanted to steal it?
所以才成为基德的目标吗
No.
不对
Mr. Mouri,
毛利先生
I wonder if you could go to the castle with me after we go back to Tokyo.
回东京后可以陪我一起去城堡吗
I'd be glad to.
非常乐意
Can I go with you?
也让我同行好吗
Me too.
我也是
Please let me film it.
拜托 让我一起去拍摄
I want to go too.
我也想去
Fine, then everyone, let's just go together.
好 大家一起去吧
What is happening here?
怎么回事
The looks in these people's eyes all changed.
大家的眼神都变了
Do they all want to have the second egg to themselves?
难道都想独占第二颗蛋吗
Be good.
好乖
We stopped the bleeding.
血已经止住了
As soon as the wound is healed, it could fly again.
只要伤口愈合了 就能飞了
Really? That's perfect.
真的吗 太好了
Luckily, Hattori's sprain isn't so bad.
服部还好只是轻微的扭伤
Did Kid die?
基德是不是死了呢
That guy wouldn't die so easily.
那个家伙不会因为这点事情就死掉的
Maybe he's already on this ship.
搞不好已经在这船上了
I'm coming.
来了
Nice, what a great look on your face.
不错哦 这个表情
I just filmed it.
我拍下来了
What is he doing?
他这是干嘛啊
Ran,
小兰
we are here to visit you.
我们来找你玩了
Miss Kosaka, Mr. Nishino, you are here too.
夏美小姐和西野先生也一起啊
Please come in.
请进
Thanks.
打扰了
Thank you.
失礼了
I should leave now.
我还是算了吧
That's right. He must be shy because there are so many beauties in the room.
对哦 因为都是美女 他害羞了
That's so adorable.
真可爱
We forgot another beauty. I'll go get her.
还忘了一位美女 我去叫她
It's Seiran, right?
是青兰小姐吧
Let's go, little one.
我们走吧 小鬼
Do I have to go too?
我也要去吗
Okay, thank you.
好的 谢谢你们
I'll right back. Please wait for a second.
我马上就好 请稍等一下
Grigori.
格里戈尔
Is that a picture of your boyfriend?
那该不会是男朋友的照片吧
Well...
差不多吧
That's so sweet. Everyone has a boyfriend.
真好啊 大家都有老公
I have to get Kid.
所以我一定要把基德抢到手
If it's so easy for you to get him,
如果连你都抢得到手
the police wouldn't have worked so hard.
警察还需要这么辛苦吗
Natsumi, so you have been living in Paris since you were 20?
夏美小姐20岁起就住在巴黎吗
Yes, so sometimes my Japanese sounds weird.
是啊 所以有时候我的日文会很怪
Speaking of weird Japanese,
说到怪怪的日文
I don't know why I just remembered a sentence from my childhood.
我小时候有一句话不知道为什么印象特别深刻
What is that?
什么话
Posledniyvolshebnikveka.
巴鲁雪尼枯卡塔梅卡
I think it means, "Posle, did you buy the meat?"
我想是问巴鲁雪 肉买了吗的意思
However, that name doesn't ring a bell at all.
可是我对这个人名完全没印象
Natsumi, the color of your eyes.
夏美小姐的眼珠颜色
That's right. It's gray.
没错 是灰色的
The same color as the eyes of my mother and grandma.
我母亲和祖母也是这样的颜色
I think I inherited them from my great grandma.
我想应该是曾祖母的遗传吧
Speaking of which,
这么说的话
Seiran, your eyes are also gray.
青兰小姐的眼珠不也是灰色的吗
That's true. Do all the Chinese have gray eyes?
真的耶 中国人都是灰色的吗
Seiran means "blue orchid" in Japanese.
青兰小姐的名字写作青色兰花
My name means "orchid" too.
我的名字也是兰
That's the Japanese transcription.
你们念的是日文发音
In Chinese, it should be pronounced as Chinglan.
中文应该念青兰
Chinglan.
青兰
That's right, "sei" being "ching" and "ran" being "lan". My last name is "pusi" in Chinese,
对 se是青 ran是兰 我的姓念浦思
so my name is Pusi Chinglan.
所以是浦思青兰
Ran's Chinese pronunciation is the same as the Japanese's.
兰的中文发音和日文一样耶
Yes, your last name would be Maoli in Chinese.
是啊 你的姓中文念做毛利
So my name is Maoli Lan?
那我叫做毛利兰喽
What a cute pronunciation.
发音好可爱哦
What about me?
那我呢
Yours is Lingmu Yuanzi.
你的名字念做铃木园子
Lingmu Yuanzi.
铃木园子
Seiran, I think we are about the same age.
青兰小姐的年纪应该和我差不多吧
I'm 27 years old.
是的 27岁
We really are the same age. Which month were you born in?
果然一样 你几月生的
May. May 5th.
5月 5月5日
My birthday is May 3rd. Our birthday are only two days away.
我是5月3日 差两天而已
Your birthday is one day away from mine.
那你们两个都只和我差一天耶
One day away. May 4th.
差一天 5月4日
That's Shinichi's birthday.
和新一一样
Is it a coincidence?
这是巧合
Or...
难道
could Conan be...
难道柯南他真的是…
That's silly...
傻瓜
How would that even be possible?
怎么可能会有这种事
It must be because I miss him so much.
一定是我对他老是念念不忘的关系
I'm such a fool.
我真是个傻瓜
Natsumi, Seiran,
夏美小姐和青兰小姐
do you want to have a drink together?
要一起喝一杯吗
Is it convenient?
方便吗
Of course, please have a seat.
当然 请坐请坐
So sexy.
真性感啊
I can't stand that old man anymore.
真受不了这个老头子
Please.
那么请用
Thanks.
谢谢
Mr. Sagawa, that pendant you're wearing.
寒川先生 你那个坠子
The historian of Romanov Dynasty truly knows something.
不愧是罗曼诺夫王朝研究家
So you've noticed that.
你注意到了吗
Do you want to have a look?
要看看吗
Has he been wearing that the whole time?
他之前有戴着这项链吗
Maria.
玛丽亚
Is this the ring which belonged to Maria,
这该不会是尼古拉二世第三个女儿
the third daughter of Tsar Nicholas II?
玛丽亚的戒指吧
Since you already said that, then it must be.
你都这么说当然就是喽
Where did you get that?
你从哪里得到的
Is it real?
是真的吗
I can't jump to conclusions without an appraisal.
不详细鉴定我也不敢妄下断言
Nishino, your ball point pen is about to drop.
西野 你的圆珠笔快掉了
Thank you.
谢谢
Mr. Mouri. Is Mr. Mouri here?
毛利先生 毛利先生在吗
Are we finally going to eat?
终于要吃饭了吗
Something bad happened. Mr. Sagawa, he...
不得了了 寒川先生他
Mr. Sagawa died in his room.
寒川先生他死在房间里了
What?
什么
Mr. Sagawa.
寒川先生
He was shot in the right eye.
右眼被击中
So was Kid.
当时基德也是被击中右眼
Boy, move away.
小鬼闪到一边去
Are you all right?
不要紧吧
His face just started to get rigid.
脸颊才刚开始僵硬
The murder must have been committed 30 minutes ago.
死后差不多30分钟左右
The pendant is missing.
戒指项坠不见了
Chairman Suzuki, this is a homicide.
铃木会长 这是杀人案件
Please contact the police.
请马上联络警方
Ok.
好的
I see. We'll be right there.
知道了 马上过去
Inspector Megure.
是目暮警官
Shiratori, shouldn't you be on vacation in Karuizawa?
白鸟 你不是到轻井泽渡假了吗
It's too boring staying in the villa.
呆在别墅里实在太无聊了
Do we have a case?
有案件发生了吗
You're just in time. Let's go together.
你来得正好 我们一起过去
Officer, thanks for coming.
警官 恭候您的大驾
Come on.
真是的
Why do you always run into cases?
为什么你在的地方总是有案件
That's the God's will.
这是神的旨意吧
Or say, Mr. Mouri, you are the God.
毛利先生自己就是神吧
God of Death.
死神
Officer Shiratori's words are so harsh.
白鸟警官讲话真冲
What's with this band-aid?
你这创可贴是怎么回事
I'm fine. I got into a fight with a criminal yesterday.
没有啦 昨天和犯人打了一架
The victim is Ryu Sagawa, 32 years old.
被害者是寒川龙先生 32岁
He's a freelance photographer.
自由摄影师
Officer, the murder was committed by a robber.
警官 这是抢劫杀人
Our suspect stole the ring.
犯人偷走了戒指
Ring?
戒指
Yes.
是的
The ring which belonged to Maria, the third daughter of Tsar Nicholas II.
尼古拉二世的第三个女儿玛丽亚的戒指
Mr. Sagawa wore the ring as a pendant on his neck.
寒川把它当项链的坠子挂在脖子上
If the target is the ring, why didn't the suspect just take it from the victim's neck?
偷戒指的话只要从脖子上拿下来不就行了
The room is in a mess
可是现场被翻得乱七八糟
and even the pillow was ripped. Don't you find it weird?
连枕头都被割开了 不奇怪吗
You little fool, don't walk around.
这家伙又到处乱晃
Inspector Megure, we found this on the floor.
目暮警官 地上发现了这个
A ball point pen.
圆珠笔
M·Nishino.
M·西野
This ball point pen, Mr. Nishino,
这支圆珠笔 西野先生
is yours, right?
是你的东西没错吧
Yes.
是的
Why did it show up in Mr. Sawaga's room?
可是为什么会在寒川先生房里
You are the one who found the body, aren't you?
是你发现遗体的吧
I am.
是的
It's time to eat. So I went there to inform him.
因为开饭了 所以我去叫他
Did you enter the room at that time?
当时你有进入房间吗
No.
没有
If you didn't, why was your ball point pen
没有进去的话那你的圆珠笔
found in the room?
为什么会掉在房间里
I have no idea.
我不知道
What were you doing at half past seven?
那你7点半的时候在做什么
At around 7:10, I had a shower.
7点10分左右我淋了个浴
Then I took a nap.
然后小睡了一会儿
Dad, could it be Mr. Nishino?
爸爸 该不会是西野先生
No, it can't be.
不 不可能
If Mr. Nishino is the murderer,
如果西野先生是杀害寒川的凶手
he might also be the one who shot Kid.
那他就很有可能也是向基德射击的人
Inspector Megure.
目暮警官
When we searched the victim's room,
搜查被害人房间的时候
we found that all the tapes have gone missing.
我们发现录影带全部不见了
What?
什么
That explains the matter.
原来如此
No wonder why the whole room was turned upside down.
难怪整个房间都被翻遍了
Conan, don't run around.
柯南 你不要乱跑
It's fine. I'll watch him.
没关系 我看着他
Ran.
小兰
The criminal who has a gun might be around.
拿着枪的犯人也许就在附近游荡
You should get back.
你还是回到大家身边吧
But, what about Conan?
可是 柯南他
I'll bring him back.
我会带他回去的
Just go.
回去吧
But.
可是
Don't worry. I have it covered.
放心交给我吧
Agasa, it's me.
博士 是我
I need you to look into something for me urgently.
有件急事拜托你调查一下
What? A sniper who only shoots right eyes?
什么 专门狙击右眼的狙击手
I see. I'll get into it.
知道了 我马上调查
Call me in ten minutes.
10分钟后你再打来
Ten minutes.
10分钟
Am I being paranoid?
是我多疑了吗
I got it, Shinichi.
查到了 新一
When I had a look at the ICPO crime database,
我登录ICPO的犯罪情报网查找时
I found someone whose age, gender and origins are currently unknown.
发现年龄不详 性别未知的罪犯
The person's called Scorpion.
他被叫做 史考兵(Scorpion意为毒蝎)
Scorpion.
史考兵
Officer, I found it.
警官 找到了
It's under Mr. Nishino's bed.
在西野先生的床底下
How's that even possible?
这怎么可能
This is the conclusive evidence.
找到决定性的证据
Wait, Officer, I didn't do it.
等一下警官 不是我做的
If you are not guilty,
如果你不是犯人
why is the ring at your place?
那为什么戒指在你这里
I don't know.
我不知道
The criminal should be Scorpion.
犯人十有八九是史考兵
If Mr. Nishino is Scorpion...
如果西野先生是史考兵
Padded pillow.
麸皮枕头
Conan.
柯南
Mr. Nishino, you are allergic to feathers, aren't you?
西野先生有羽毛过敏症吧
That's right.
是啊
Then the murderer can't be Mr. Nishino.
那犯人就不可能是西野先生
What?
什么
Keep going.
你继续往下说
Because we found feather all over Mr. Sagawa's room.
因为寒川先生的房里都是羽毛
The murderer even cut through the feather pillow.
犯人连羽毛枕头都割开了
That's not something a person who's allergic to feathers will do.
羽毛过敏症的人不可能这么做
Are you really allergic to the feathers?
你真的有羽毛过敏症吗
Yes, I can testify for him.
是的 我可以为他作证
He gets sneezing fits whenever there are feathers.
他只要有一点羽毛就会不停的打喷嚏
That's why Mr. Nishino doesn't use a feather pillow.
所以西野先生的枕头不是羽毛的
I see.
原来如此
Mr. Nishino escaped from Ran's room
西野先生逃离小兰的房间
because there was a pigeon.
是因为房间里有鸽子
So who's the murderer?
那犯人到底是谁
Officer, have you heard of Scorpion before?
警官听说过史考兵吗
Scorpion?
史考兵
The bad guy specializes in stealing treasures belonging to the Romanov dynasty
专门在各国偷取罗曼诺夫王朝的宝物
and shoot his victims through the right eye.
而且专门射击对手右眼的坏人
You reminded me.
经你这么一说
That's the world's most wanted criminal.
的确有这么一个全球通缉的要犯
Are you suggesting that the murderer is that person?
难道这次的犯人也是
I think Scorpion did this.
我想应该是这个史考兵
He should also be the one who shot Kid.
狙击基德的人应该也是他
What did you say?
你说什么
Kid's monocle was broken.
基德的右眼单片眼镜被击碎了
Scorpion shot Kid.
史考兵击中基德
Because he wanted to take away the egg in Kid's hand.
因为他想夺取基德手中的蛋
How did you know about Kid?
为什么你会知道史考兵的事
Well, because, actually...
这个嘛 因为 也就是…
Hiroshi Agasa told him.
是阿笠博士告诉他的
Isn't that right,
对不对
Conan?
柯南
Yeah.
是啊
Damn it.
糟糕
I felt someone watching at me when I phoned Agasa.
原来打电话给博士时感觉到背后的目光
And that person turned out to be Officer Shiratori.
是白鸟警官的
Your secret will be exposed.
秘密会被揭穿
Does it mean Officer Shirator will find out?
莫非指的是白鸟警官
But if the murderer is Scorpion,
可是如果犯人是史考兵
why did he put the ring he stole from Mr. Sagawa's room
为什么他要把从寒川先生的房间偷来的戒指
into Mr. Nishino's room?
故意藏在西野先生的房间里呢
That I don't know.
这个我也不清楚
This is bad.
真糟糕
I can't use the tranquilizer wrist-watch in front of Officer Shiratori.
不能当着白鸟警官的面用麻醉针
Anyway.
管他的
Mr. Nishino, you know Mr. Sagawa, do you?
西野先生和寒川先生认识吧
Yesterday, when we were in the museum,
昨天在美术馆
Mr. Sagawa seemed to be surprised to meet you.
寒川先生看到西野先生时吓了一跳
Really?
真的吗
Mr. Nishino, you have lived abroad for years.
西野先生长年旅居海外
Maybe you two have met in a foreign country.
一定是在国外见过面吧
Have you met Mr. Sagawa before?
你认识寒川先生吗
Yes, when I traveled in an Asian country three years ago,
是的 三年前去亚洲旅行时
I saw him taking photos of the girl whose house was burnt down because of the war.
看见他正在拍摄因内战而被烧毁了房子的女孩
I told him to stop, but he didn't listen.
我叫他住手他不听
So I beat him up.
忍不住揍了他一顿
So, Mr. Sawaga must have held a grudge against Mr. Nishino.
那么寒川先生一定还对西野先生记恨在心
I know it.
我知道了
Mr. Nishino, you must be Scorpion.
西野先生 你就是史考兵
Mouri, we know he's not Scorpion from the feathers.
毛利老弟 从羽毛这件事就知道不是他了
That's right.
对哦
But Mr. Nishino was saved by that.
可是西野先生也因此得救了
If Mr. Sagawa wasn't killed by Scorpion,
如果寒川先生没有被史考兵杀的话
Mr. Nishino would be regarded as the thief who stole the ring.
西野先生就会被当成偷戒指的小偷
Wait a minute.
等一下
So that's what it is.
原来如此
This case is just like the two eggs.
这个案件和两颗蛋一样
We are actually investigating two cases.
是有两个案子重叠在一起
Two cases?
两个案子
That's right. That's right.
没错没错
In the first case,
第一个案件是
Mr. Sagawa tried to frame Mr. Nishino.
寒川先生想嫁祸给西野先生
In order to make everyone think that Mr. Nishino stole his ring,
他为了使西野先生被当成偷戒指的小偷
he showed his ring to everyone on purpose.
故意在大家面前展示他的戒指
When Mr. Nishino was in the shower,
趁西野先生淋浴时
Mr. Sagawa snuck into his room and put the ring under his bed.
潜入他的房间把戒指藏在床下
After that, Mr. Sagawa stole Mr. Nishino's ball point pen
然后再偷走西野先生的圆珠笔
to let everyone believe that Mr. Nishino is the thief.
为的是让西野先生被当成偷戒指的小偷
However, the second case happened next.
可是没料到此时第二个案件发生了
Mr. Sagawa was shot
寒川先生他
by Scorpion.
被史考兵射杀了
I'm afraid the reason why he was killed is that
目的恐怕是
the photos he took and his ring are able to reveal Scorpion's true identity.
拍到了能揭穿史考兵真面目的录影带和戒指
However, the ring he wore on his neck went missing.
可是挂在脖子上的戒指不见了
So Scorpion searched the entire room.
史考兵便翻遍整个房间寻找
Uncle, you are so brilliant. You are worthy of the name the famous detective.
叔叔好棒 真是名推理
That's just a piece of cake.
对我来说小事一桩
So, Scorpion might be hiding somewhere on this ship.
那么 史考兵恐怕还躲在船上的某个角落
About that,
关于这件事
one of the lifeboats went missing.
救生艇少了一艘
What?
什么
So, Scorpion escaped using the lifeboat?
那么史考兵乘救生艇逃走了
We already searched the area,
已经立刻展开紧急搜寻了
but it might be difficult to find him.
可是估计很难找到
He got away.
被他逃走了
Did Scorpion really get away?
史考兵真的逃走了吗
Anyway, since we know that the killer is not on the ship now,
无论如何 知道杀人犯已经不在船上
everyone could rest assured.
我们至少可以松一口气了
Yes, we can stop worrying.
是的 可以放心了
But Scorpion is still looking for the other egg.
可是史考兵还觊觎着另一颗蛋
He might show up in Kosaka's castle.
他很可能出现在香坂家的城堡里
No, he might have already headed to that place.
不 他应该已经去了
Inspector Megure,
目暮警官
when we arrive at Tokyo tomorrow,
明天到达东京后
I'd like to go to the Castle with everyone.
我也想和夏美小姐他们一同前往城堡
Okay, I agree.
好的 就这么办
Hey listen,
听到了吗
we can't take you with us this time.
这次绝对不能带你去了
No, Conan should go with us.
不 带柯南一起去吧
What?
什么
His unique way of thinking might be of help.
他独特的思考角度也许会有帮助
This boy's way of thinking?
这家伙的吗
I am so angry at Conan.
柯南那家伙 气死人了
That's right. He never contacted us after coming back from Okasa.
真是的 去了大阪就完全没和我们联系了
He completely forgot that he's also a member of the Detective Boys.
他根本忘了自己是少年侦探团的一员
Agasa, you still haven't found your driver's license?
博士 驾照还没找到吗
I remembered putting it here.
我记得放在这里的啊
If you don't hurry, Conan will be one step ahead of us again.
动作不快点的话会被柯南捷足先登哦
Ai, you are so good at finding things.
小哀真会找东西
We've got another trouble.
我又找到了另一个麻烦
Mr. Mouri,
毛利先生
did Mr. Sawaga's ring really belong to Maria before?
寒川先生的戒指真的是玛丽亚的吗
It was given to Inspector Megure for appraisal.
已经交给目暮警官去鉴定了
Maria was the kindest one among the four sisters,
玛丽亚是四姐妹中最温柔的
who had a pair of gray eyes.
有着一双灰色的大眼睛
Gray eyes?
灰色
Like Natsumi and Seiran.
和夏美 青兰一样
After the Russian Revolutions, the Tsar's families were all executed.
你们应该知道俄国革命后 皇帝一家被枪杀
But only Maria and her brother's corpses weren't found.
只有玛丽亚和皇太子不见遗体
Is that so?
是吗
What a beautiful castle.
好漂亮的城堡
It's like the Scholoss Neuschwanstein in Germany.
很像德国的新天鹅堡(Schloss Neuschwanstein)
It's said to have been the model for Cinderella's castle.
那可是灰姑娘城堡的原型
By the way, why is this a German style building?
这么说起来为什么会是德国风格的建筑
Isn't Natsumi's great grandma a Russian?
夏美的曾祖母不是俄国人吗
Conan.
柯南
How are you doing?
你好吗
Agasa, why are you here?
博士怎么也来了
I got a phone from Conan
接到柯南的电话
and decided to drop by since I was on the road anyway.
出来兜风顺便过来看看
Here, I upgraded it according to your request.
给 按你的要求做了个增强版
Thanks.
谢了
But why did you bring them here?
可是为什么带他们来
They slipped into my car when I wasn't looking.
他们趁我不注意钻进了车里
This is like the castle in the fairy tale.
好像童话中的城堡哦
There must be a lot of treasures inside.
里面藏有很多宝藏耶
How many bowls of grilled eel rice can I have?
可以吃几碗鳗鱼饭啊
Listen to me, you are not allowed to enter.
你们给我听好了 绝对不许进去
Fine.
好的
We know.
我们知道了
Why did they agree so easily?
怎么回答得这么爽快
Mr. Inui is so slow.
乾先生好慢哦
He said he needed to go somewhere else first.
他说要先去别的地方
Sorry, it took me a while to prepare.
不好意思 我花了点时间准备
Why are you carrying a bag?
你背的这个是什么行李啊
Are you planning to go for an adventure?
打算去探险的吗
It never hurts to be more prepared.
有备无患嘛
Be careful, Scorpion might be around.
小心点 史考兵也许就在身边
I know.
我知道
Please lock the door.
请把门锁上
Don't let the kids in.
不要让小孩子进来
Okay.
好的
Okay, let's get started.
好 我们也开始行动了
What do you want to do?
你们要做什么
Look for the treasures.
先找到宝藏啊
There has to be another entrance.
一定还有别的入口
Let's go find it.
我们去找吧
This is the Knight's room.
这里是骑士房
It is decorated with suits of armors and tapestries in Western style.
用西洋的盔甲和壁毯装饰
This is the Lady's lounge.
这里是贵妇人房
The late mistress used to spend a whole day here
太太常常在这里呆上一整天
because she said this was the most comfortable room.
因为她说这个房间最舒适
This is the Tsar's Gallery.
这里是皇帝房
I'd like to use the restroom.
我想去厕所
It's on the right of the hallway.
厕所在走廊右边
Just as I thought.
正如我所料
The egg doesn't seem to be here, but it doesn't matter.
好像没有那颗蛋 不过没关系
What is happening here?
这是怎么回事
Old Master Kiichi created this trap 80 years ago.
80年前喜一老爷做的防盗装置
There are other traps like this in the castle to protect the treasure from thieves.
城堡里还有其他的机关
Please be careful.
请小心
It means that you shouldn't act on your own, Mr. Inui.
也就是说请你不要擅自行动 乾先生
The only thing you need is a flashlight.
你只需要手电筒就够了
Old Master Kiichi really liked setting traps.
喜一先生果然喜欢机关
So it means.
也就是说
Is there a basement in this castle?
这座城堡有地下室吗
No.
没有
What about Natsumi's great grandpa's room on the first floor?
那么一楼曾祖父的房间呢
There's an old study.
有一间办公室
Please come in.
请进
There are some old photos of Old Master Kiichi
这里陈列了喜一老爷的照片
and photography works at that time.
以及当时的一些摄影作品
Natsumi, where are your great grandma's photos?
夏美小姐 曾祖母的照片呢
Well, about that...There aren't any.
说到那个 一张也没有
So I don't know what my great grandma looked like.
所以我不知道曾祖母的长相
That's strange. There are so many photos of Old Master Kiichi.
奇怪 明明有那么多喜一先生的照片
Isn't this man Rasputin?
这个男人不是拉斯普钦吗
That's right. His signature is even on the photo.
没错 上面还有他的签名Г·拉斯普钦
G. Rasputin.
Г·拉斯普钦
Dad, who's Rasputin?
爸爸 拉斯普钦是谁
I only know that he was called an evil of the century.
我只知道他是历史的罪人
He was also called the Mad Monk
他被称为怪僧拉斯普钦
and is said to be responsible for the ruin of the Romanovs
善于奉承皇帝一家
because he was good at fawning on the Tsar's family.
以至于造成了罗曼诺夫王朝的灭亡
For a time, he had even come into power of the country.
他曾经一度掌控了政权
At last, he as killed by Duke Yusupove, a member of the royal family.
最后被皇室贵族尤斯波夫公爵所杀
When his body was found by the river,
在河川发现了他的遗体
his skull caved in
头盖骨凹陷
and one of his eyes was missing.
一只眼睛被挖掉了
One of his eyes?
一只眼睛
Mr. Inui,
乾先生
finding the egg is more important than the story of Rasputin, isn't it?
比起拉斯普钦现在找蛋才是最重要的吧
That's right.
话虽如此
But how can we find it in such a big house?
这么大的房子要从何找起
Uncle, give me this.
叔叔 借我一下
What are you doing?
你干什么
There's wind coming up.
下面有风吹上来
There has to be a secret basement.
下面有秘密地下室
What?
什么
So,
这么说
Old Master Kiichi who liked to create traps
喜欢制作机关的喜一先生
must have hidden the switch somewhere.
一定把开关藏在哪里了
What are those?
那是什么
They are Russian letters.
是俄文字母
Can we open the door of the secret basement with that?
用这个就能开启秘室的门吗
We have to enter the password.
应该有密码
Mr. Sergei, can you type Russian letters for us?
西鲁先生你来按俄文
Memories. It has to be the word memories.
回忆 一定是回忆的俄文
ВОСПОМИНАНИЕ.
ВОСПОМИНАНИЕ(回忆)
Weird.
奇怪
Then it should be Kiichi Kosaka.
那就是喜一香坂
КИИУИ КОСАКА
КИИУИ КОСАКА(喜一 香坂)
Nothing happened.
一点动静都没有
Natsumi, have you heard anything about the password?
夏美小姐 你有没有听说过关于这个密码的事情
Not at all.
完全没有
Posledniyvolshebnikveka.
巴鲁雪尼枯卡塔梅卡
Natsumi has said that before.
夏美小姐说过的那句话
Maybe that's Russian.
说不定是俄文呢
What is he talking about?
他说什么啊
Don't interrupt.
别插嘴
Natsumi, Posle what?
夏美小姐 巴鲁雪什么
volshebnik veka.
尼枯卡塔梅卡
Posledniyvolshebnikveka.
巴鲁雪尼枯卡塔梅卡
Maybe it's the pause.
也许断句不对吧
Posledniy volshebnik veka...
巴鲁雪尼 枯卡答 梅卡…
Posledniy...
巴鲁雪尼…
Could it be ВОЛШЕБНИК КОНЦА ВЕКА?
会不会是ВОЛШЕБНИК КОНЦА ВЕКА
That's right. It is ВОЛШЕБНИК КОНЦА ВЕКА.
对了 是ВОЛШЕБНИК КОНЦА ВЕКА
What does it mean?
那是什么意思
In English, it should be, "The Last Wizard of the Century."
英文是 The Last Wisard Of The Century
In Japanese, it's...
日文应该是…
The Last Wizard of the Century.
世纪末的魔术师
The Last Wizard of the Century. I seem to have heard of that before.
世纪末的魔术师 好像在哪里听过
Kid's letter.
基德的预告函
That's right. What a coincidence.
没错 真是太巧合了
Coincidence? Is that really a coincidence?
巧合 真的是巧合吗
I'll type first.
先按按看吧
ВОЛШЕБНИК КОНЦА ВЕКА
ВОЛШЕБНИК КОНЦА ВЕКА
What's that sound?
什么声音
That's...
这个是
What on earth?
竟然有这种事
Awesome, kid.
真了不起啊 小鬼
No, it's also locked here.
不行 这边也锁起来了
Come on.
可恶
If we don't move faster, the treasure will be taken away by others.
再拖拖拉拉的宝藏就要被别人拿走了
Ai, where are you going?
小哀 你要去哪里
I just want to check that tower.
我只是去看看那座塔
Ai, what's in there?
灰原 那里有什么啊
It has to be the treasure.
一定是宝藏
Great.
太好了
It's opened.
打开了
Haibara, there's nothing.
灰原 什么都没有嘛
I didn't say there was.
我没说有东西啊
Stop looking. Let's go home.
不要找了 我们快回去吧
What?
怎么了
Oh no.
糟糕了
It hurts, you guys.
好痛哦 你们…
Your belly is so soft.
好软的肚子哦
Thanks to you, I didn't get hurt.
托你的福我才没有受伤
What is that?
这是什么
It's a snake.
是蛇
It's not a snake.
不是蛇啦
It's a rope ladder, but an old one.
是绳梯 已经很旧了
It was hung there before, but broke afterwards.
本来挂在上面 后来断掉了
It freaked me out.
吓了我一大跳
What do we do? Should we wait for Agasa to come and save us?
怎么办 在这里等博士来救我们
Or should we keep moving?
还是往前走
Well.
这个嘛
Of course we will...
当然是
Let's go.
Let's go(我们走)
By the way, Natsumi,
说起来 夏美小姐
why would the password be the last wizard of the century?
为什么密码是世纪末的魔术师
That might be my great grandpa's nickname.
这大概是曾祖父的称号吧
He attended the World's Fair in 1900 when he was 16.
曾祖父16岁时参加1900年万国博览会
and exhibited the marionette at that time.
展出了活动木偶
After that, he went to Russia and lived there.
后来就到了俄国居住
I see.
原来如此
The year 1900 truly is the end of a century.
1900年的确是世纪末啊
There's still road ahead. This tunnel is deep.
还有路啊 真深啊
What's wrong?
怎么了
I think I heard something.
我隐约听到了声音
Is it Scorpion?
是史考兵吗
I'll go have a look.
我去看看
Conan.
柯南
I'll go with him.
我过去就好
Mr. Mouri, please stay here with everyone else.
毛利先生和大家一起呆在这里
Okay.
了解
It's you.
是你
You guys.
是你们
Conan.
柯南
Geez...
受不了
In this world,
在这个世界上
I got your love.
我得到了你的爱
What are these kids doing here?
他们到底打算来干嘛啊
It's fine, Mr. Mouri.
没关系啦 毛利先生
The more the merrier!
人多比较热闹
But...
可是
To solve all the mysteries...
去解开所有的谜…
You still...
你依然…
It's a dead end.
没有路了
Are we on the wrong path?
走错路了吗
It can't be. There's supposed to be only one path.
不可能的 应该只有一条路
Which means, there are traps too.
也就是说 这里也有机关
So many birds.
好多鸟
That's weird. That big bird has two heads.
奇怪 只有那只大鸟有两个头
Two-headed vulture, the symbol of Tsar.
双头鹫 皇帝的象征
Is it the sun which is behind the crown?
王冠后面的是太阳吗
The sun...
太阳…
Light...
光…
Could it be...
难不成是…
Officer Shiratori,
白鸟警官
please shine your flashlight at the crown on the two headed vulture.
把手电筒的光集中在双头鹫的王冠上
It flashed.
发光了
What's happening?
怎么了
Everyone, back off.
大家快退开
The entrance.
入口
I see.
原来如此
This crown is formed by photometers.
这个王冠是由光度计组合成的
This is so cool.
好酷哦
Such a brilliant mechanism.
好厉害的机关
It's like we are in an egg.
好像在蛋里面哦
What is this?
这是什么
Looks like a coffin.
好像是个棺木
It's a Western style coffin made of wood.
虽然造型是西洋式的 可材料是木头的
Speaking of which, that's a huge lock.
话说回来 这个锁可真大啊
Natsumi, the key.
夏美小姐 那把钥匙
That's right.
对了
It does fit into the lock.
真的是这把钥匙呢
So, what's inside of this coffin...
这样说来 这个棺木中…
Can I open it?
可以打开吗
Yes.
可以
It's heavy.
好重
There's a skeleton and an egg.
遗体一具 还有一颗蛋
The skeleton holds the egg on its chest.
抱着蛋一起沉睡
Natsumi, is this your great grandpa?
夏美小姐 这具遗体是曾祖父吗
No, I think it should be my great grandmother.
不 我想应该是曾祖母
In Yokosuka, there's only my great grandfather's grave.
横须贺只有曾祖父的坟墓
I always found that strange.
我一直觉得不可思议
Maybe it's because she was a Russian
也许因为她是俄国人
who couldn't get a funeral in an ordinary cemetery.
所以无法葬在历代祖先的坟墓里
Natsumi, this may be a bad time,
夏美小姐 现在也许时机不对
but can I have a look at that egg?
但是可以让我看看那颗蛋吗
Okay.
好的
Please.
请
There's a hole at the bottom.
底部有个小洞
It's empty.
空的
How could it be?
这怎么可能
What happened?
到底怎么回事
It's empty.
空的
Isn't it like a Matryoshka?
那是套娃(Matryoshka)吧
Matryoshka?
套娃
I have that kind of doll at home.
我们家有那种娃娃
My father's friend bought it from Russia as a gift.
是爸爸的朋友从俄罗斯买给我的
What is a Matryoshka Doll?
那个套娃是什么啊
It's a set of dolls of decreasing size placed one inside another,
在娃娃里面一层层放进更小的娃娃
a Russian toy.
是俄罗斯的娃娃玩具
That might be true. Check this.
看来应该是这样 你们请看
The grooves inside should be used to hold something in place.
这里面的沟槽应该是用来固定的
Damn it, if we had the other egg here, we could confirm that.
可恶 如果有那颗蛋就可以确认了
We have it.
有那颗蛋啊
I knew you would need this,
我早料到会用得着
so I borrowed it from Chairman Suzuki.
所以跟铃木会长借来了
You didn't take it out secretly, did you?
你该不会是偷偷拿来的吧
No way, how's that possible?
真是的 这怎么可能
Let's try it.
马上来试试看
It fits right in there.
刚刚好
So, Old Master Kiichi didn't make two eggs
也就是说喜一先生并非做了两个蛋
but split it in two parts.
而是一个蛋分为两个
You seem to have doubts.
你好像还有疑问
Yeah.
是啊
There should be another mechanism.
我觉得这颗蛋应该还有机关
The mechanism which fits the nickname 'the last wizard of the century'.
一个符合世纪末魔术师的机关
By the way, those gems are pretty.
话说回来 这些钻石真漂亮
No, those are not gems,
不 这好像不是钻石
just glass.
只是一般的玻璃
Glass.
玻璃
Wait. Come to think of it,
等一下 说起来
the glass on the top of the egg,
蛋盖上的玻璃
Old Master Kiichi's room,
喜一先生的房间
the light and mechanism...
光线与机关…
And the platform.
还有那个座台
That's right.
没错
The glass pieces on the inside and outside of the eggs are lenses.
蛋里的玻璃具有镜片的功能
Mr. Sergei, I need this egg.
西鲁先生 蛋借我一下
What do you want to do again, boy?
你这小子又想干什么
Wait, Mr. Mouri.
等一下嘛 毛利先生
Do you need my help?
有什么需要我帮忙的
I need your flashlight.
准备手电筒
Please concentrate the light and put the flashlight on the platform.
把手电筒的光集中 放进座台里
Okay.
了解
Mr. Serger, Mr. Hoshi,
西鲁先生 青兰小姐
please blow out the candles.
把蜡烛吹灭
What are you going to do?
你到底要做什么
Just wait and see.
看着吧
The egg became transparent.
蛋变透明了
Even without turning the key,
虽然没有上发条
the Tsar's family is rising!
皇帝一家的人偶竟然升了起来
There are photometers inside the egg.
蛋的内部设计有光度计
What!?
怎么了
This is...
这是…
The picture of Nicholas II's whole family.
尼古拉皇帝全家人的照片
So they are not looking at the book
原来蛋里面他们所看的不是书
but the album.
而是相册
That's why it's called the Memories Egg.
所以取名为回忆
If the Tsar's families weren't killed,
如果皇帝一家人没有遭到杀害
this egg should be a very precious gift.
这个蛋可以说是最珍贵的礼物
Your great grandpa really was the last wizard of the century.
真不愧为世纪末的魔术师啊 你的曾祖父
He would be glad to hear that.
曾祖父如果听到 一定会很高兴
Natsumi,
夏美小姐
that's your great grandpa's photo, isn't it?
那张照片是你曾祖父吧
There are two people sitting on the bench.
那张两个人一起坐在椅子上的照片
It is.
真的耶
So the person next to him is your great grandmother?
那么说旁边的就是曾祖母咯
She is.
那是我的曾祖母
I finally saw her.
终于见到了
That's the only photo which was taken in Japan.
只有那张照片是在日本拍的
It must've been added to the album by Old Master Kiichi.
应该是喜一老爷后来加上去的
This woman...
这个人…
looks just like Natsumi.
和夏美小姐好像
This egg is a great legacy of Old Master Kiichi,
这颗蛋是喜一先生
no, I should say a great legacy of Japan.
不 应该说是日本的伟大遗产
Russia will give up the ownership of the two eggs.
俄罗斯将放弃这两颗蛋的所有权
It only has a value if it's in your hand.
只有你拥有它才有价值
Thank you.
谢谢你
But the egg inside belongs to Chairman Suzuki.
可是里面的蛋是铃木会长的
I'll try to persuade Chairman Suzuki.
铃木会长那边由我去说
He'll understand.
他一定能理解的
By the way, where did Mr. Inui go?
说起来乾先生跑到哪里去了
I didn't see
拉斯普钦的照片
Rasputin's photo there.
没有出现
Wasn't he close to the Tsar's family?
他不是跟皇帝一家人很好吗
Indeed, we saw it in Old Master Kiichi's study.
的确 在喜一先生房里有看到
That Г can't be...
那个Г 该不会是…
This finally ended in a satisfactory way.
一切终于圆满结束了
That's...
那是…
Next...
接下来…
Watch out.
危险
What are you doing, Conan?
你搞什么啊 柯南
Don't pick it up, Ran.
不要捡 小兰
Ran.
小兰
Shinichi.
新一
Everybody, get down.
大家快趴下
The egg...
蛋…
Damn it, I won't let you get away.
可恶 我不会让你逃走的
Don't go.
不要去
Mr. Mouri, please take care of them.
毛利先生 这边麻烦你了
Shinichi.
新一
Mr. Inui.
乾先生
Damn it.
可恶
There has to be a switch that can open the door from the inside.
这里一定有从里面打开的开关
Only this piece has a different shape.
只有这块形状不一样
Wait.
等一下
Do you want to get out of here alone?
你想一个人逃出去吗
I won't let you get away.
我不会让你得逞的
I know who you are.
我知道你的真面目了
You pretend to be a Chinese,
假装是中国人
but are actually a Russian.
其实是俄国人
Am I right?
我猜对了吧
You are the descendant of Rasputin, the Mad Monk.
怪僧拉斯普钦的后裔
Seiran.
青兰小姐
What's going on? The road is blocked.
怎么回事 道路被封死了
We can't get out?
那我们出不去了吗
Everybody, follow me.
大家跟着我走
What?
什么
Cut the nonsense, just follow me.
别废话了 跟着我走就对了
I see.
知道了
I didn't even notice that.
一开始我竟然没注意
It's Sagawa's voice.
是寒川的声音
If I rearrange the letters in your name Seiran Hoshi,
将浦思青兰重新排列组合
it'll become Rasputin.
就变成拉斯普钦了
Weren't you... weren't you already killed by me?
你不是…你不是已经被我杀死了吗
You think that some of the treasures from the Romanov Dynasty
你认为罗曼诺夫王朝的财宝
should be left to Rasputin who was close to the Tsar's family.
应该留给和皇帝一家关系密切的拉斯普钦
So you want to get all the treasures on behalf of your ancestor.
所以你代替你的祖先们想把所有的财宝弄到手
You insist on shooting your opponents' right eyes
而执意攻击对手的右眼
because you want to honor your ancestor who was brutally killed.
也是为了缅怀惨遭杀害的祖先
Mr. Inui.
乾先生
It's just me.
只有我一个人
What?
什么
This is a voice-changing bow-tie
这个是蝴蝶结型变声器
which could change my voice to anybody else.
它可以变成任何人的声音
Who the hell are you?
你到底是谁
I'm Conan Edogawa, a detective.
江户川柯南 是个侦探
You killed Mr. Sagawa
你杀害寒川先生
because you were afraid that he would expose your true identity.
是因为你怕他发现你的真面目
Mr. Sagawa liked to film others
寒川先生到别人房间时
when he went to people's rooms.
习惯拍摄录影带
It happened so fast, so you forgot to flip the photo over.
因为是刹那间发生的事 你忘了把照片翻转过去
That's not your boyfriend's photo,
那根本不是男友的照片
but Grigori Rasputin's.
而是格里戈尔·拉斯普钦的照片
The word Grigori starts with the letter G,
格里戈尔的英文开头字母是G
which is Г in Russian.
而俄文则是Г
That's why I wasn't reminded of your relationship with him
所以 当我在喜一先生房里
when I saw Г Rasputin's photos
看到Г·拉斯普钦的照片时
in Old Master Kiichi's study.
也没有立即联想起来
You thought that Sagawa took a picture of Rasputin's photo,
你以为寒川拍到了拉斯普钦的照片
so you murdered him.
所以把他杀了
Isn't that right, Seiran?
对吗 青兰小姐
No, or I should call you Scorpion.
不 应该叫你史考兵
You know a lot of things, kid.
你倒是很清楚嘛 小鬼
You killed Mr. Inui because
你杀害乾先生是因为
he saw you attaching the silencer onto your pistol.
你在装消音器时被他看到了
You said as if you were there.
好像你都看到似的
As for your reason to kill Uncle Mouri,
而你要杀叔叔
it's because he badmouthed Rasputin.
是因为他说了拉斯普钦的坏话
Dad, who's Rasputin?
爸爸 拉斯普钦是谁
I only know that he was called an evil of the century.
我只知道他是历史的罪人
You even tried to kill Ran.
你甚至连小兰都想杀
Have you finished?
说够了没有
I feel sorry for you, but you have to die.
虽然有点可怜 你也去死吧
Is that pistol Walther PPK/S?
那把手枪是Walther PPK/S吧
So, the maximum capacity would be 8 bullets.
弹匣只能装8颗子弹
One for Mr. Inui, one for Uncle Mouri, one for Ran.
乾先生 叔叔 小兰各一发
You just fired 5 times just now.
刚刚在这里开了5枪
So, there are no bullets left in your gun.
你已经没有子弹了吧
Let me teach you something.
我教你一件事
If you load the magazine with eight bullets
枪膛里面已经有子弹的状况下
when there was already a bullet in the chamber,
再装上有8发子弹的弹匣
you'll have nine bullets in total.
如此一来就可以有9发子弹
Which means, there's still one bullet in the pistol.
也就是说 这把枪里还有一发子弹
Then shoot me,
那你开枪吧
if there really is one.
如果真的还有子弹的话
Stupid child.
笨小鬼
Why?
为什么
Too bad for you, Scorpion,
真不凑巧 史考兵
I asked Agasa to make these glasses
这副眼镜是我拜托博士
with bullet-proof glass.
用特制硬化镜片做的
Conan, are you all right?
柯南 你不要紧吧
I'm fine.
还好
Let's get out of here.
我们快点逃出去
Conan.
柯南
We're saved...
得救了
No, the castle is on fire.
不好了 城堡着火了
Conan.
柯南
Shinichi.
新一
You fool.
笨蛋
Conan.
柯南
What? You are so loud.
什么事 吵死人了
This egg was taken back from Scorpion by Officer Shiratori.
这个蛋是白鸟警官从史考兵手上夺回来的
Officer Shiratori.
白鸟警官
Where is Scorpion?
那么史考兵在哪里
She was arrested and sent away in a car.
被逮捕了 用车子把她送走了
Scorpion is Seiran.
史考兵就是青兰小姐
What?
什么
Seiran is Scorpion?
青兰小姐是史考兵
Natsumi, please take it.
这个交还给夏美小姐
Thank you.
谢谢
Seiran, the girl with beautiful legs, is Scorpion.
有双美腿的青兰小姐 竟然是史考兵
Natsumi,
夏美小姐
I'm sorry that things became like this.
对不起 没想到会变成这样
It's fine. Even if the castle was burnt down,
不 就算城堡烧毁了
I still have the masterpiece left by my great grandpa.
我还有曾祖父留下的伟大作品
Besides, I think the basement should be fine.
而且我想地下室应该不会有事
That's right. After this comes to an end,
是啊 等事情告一段落后
we can bury Old Madam in Old Master Kiichi's grave.
把曾祖母的遗体移去和喜一老爷葬在一起
At last, Kid still didn't show up.
结果基德还是没有出现
Maybe he really is dead.
也许他真的死了
No, he's still alive.
不 那家伙还活着
Uncle Mouri already fell asleep.
叔叔已经睡着了
Looks like he's really tired.
看来他真的很累了
We can't blame him. He's too exhausted.
没办法啊 太辛苦了
Sister Ran.
小兰姐姐
Thanks for saving me in the castle.
谢谢你在城堡里救了我一命
You were so cool at that time.
当时的柯南好帅哦
Just like Shinichi.
好像新一一样
You were like Shinichi so much at that time.
真的好像新一
Ran.
小兰
But you two are not the same person.
可是你们不是同一个人吧
Right?
对不对
Conan.
柯南
I can't hide it from her anymore.
瞒不下去了
Well... Ran.
那个…小兰
Actually, I, I am...
其实 我 真的是…
Shinichi.
新一
You are Shinichi?
真的是新一吗
Why did you ask like that?
你怎么这样问我
I heard that you were involved in a case, so I dropped by to check on you.
我听说你卷入一起案件 特地赶回来看你的
How's that possible?
这怎么可能
You fool.
傻瓜
What is wrong with you? Why didn't you even call me?
你到底怎么回事 都不和我联络
Sorry, I have so many cases to deal with.
不好意思 有太多案件要处理
I don't have so much time to stay tonight.
今晚也没时间久留
Wait, let me get you a towel.
等一下 我去拿毛巾给你擦擦
Wait, Kaitou Kid.
等一下 怪盗基德
I was totally fooled by you.
完全被你骗了
I never thought that you would disguise as Officer Shiratori.
没想到你会化装成白鸟警官
Shiratori, you made a great contribution this time.
白鸟 这次你立下大功了
What did you say?
你说什么
I just came back from Karuizawa.
我才从轻井泽回来
You knew that something would happen on the ship, right?
你知道船上发生了案件吧
I wasn't certain,
虽然不是很确定
but I tapped the wireless phone on the ship.
但是我窃听了船上的无线电话
What's more,
还有一点
you stole that egg
你偷取那颗蛋
only to return it to Natsume.
为的是要物归原主还给夏美小姐
You knew that Old Master Kiichi, the creator of the egg
你知道那颗蛋的制作者喜一
was called the last wizard of the century.
被称为世纪末的魔术师
That's why you called yourself that in your letter.
所以那封预告函上才那样写
What else did you find?
你还发现了什么
Natsumi's great grandmother is
夏美小姐的曾祖母
the third daughter of Nicholas II.
就是尼古拉二世的三女儿玛丽亚
Maria's body was never found.
玛丽亚的遗体没有被发现
Because she was saved by Old Master Kiichi and escaped to Japan before the execution.
那是因为她在枪杀前被喜一先生救走逃到了日本
They fell in love with each other
他们两人之间萌生了爱情
and had a child.
生下了孩子
However, she passed away soon after she gave birth.
但是不久后她就去世了
Old Master Kiichi sold the gems Maria had brought with her and built a castle
喜一先生为了从俄国革命军手中保护玛丽亚的遗体
in order to protect Maria's body from the Russian Revolutionary troops.
卖掉了她带来的宝石 盖了城堡
The castle is a German-style architecture instead of a Russian-style one
之所以不盖成俄国式 而盖成德国式建筑
because Maria's mother, Queen Alexandra, was German.
是因为她的母亲亚历山德拉皇后是德国人
So,
就这样
Maria's body and that egg were buried in the basement.
玛丽亚的遗体和那颗蛋一起被埋葬在地下室中
Then, Old Master Kiichi left a clue in the other egg,
而在另一颗蛋中留下了城堡的线索
waiting for his descendants to find the castle.
等待着子孙来发现它
If you think about it that way, all the mysteries are solved.
只要仔细想一下 谜题就能全部解开了
Let me give you some advice,
给你一句忠告
some things are better left unsolved.
世上有些事最好让它永远成为谜
Indeed.
的确
Maybe this puzzle should never be solved.
这个谜不要去解开或许比较好
I have another mystery for you, the famous detective.
还有一个谜题你解得开吗 名侦探
Why would I show up wearing Shinichi Kudo's face
为什么我要以工藤新一的样子出现
in order to save a tricky enemy.
去解救一个棘手的敌人
Shinichi.
新一
Idiot, what kind of question is that?
笨蛋 这算什么谜题嘛
You came to my rescue
你会替我解围
because I saved that pigeon.
是感谢我救了那只鸽子
Am I right?
对吗
Why didn't you stop him, Conan?
为什么不留住他啊 柯南
Because Brother Shinichi said he'd be back.
因为新一哥哥说他会回来的呀
Fine, next time you meet him,
好吧 下次遇到他的时候
you should do this to him.
就这么对付他
It's better not to come back for the moment.
暂时还是不要回来的好